<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Philodev Blog</title><link>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Philodev Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 14:20:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical Job Interview questions 2022</title><link>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-06-customer-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 14:20:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-06-customer-search/</guid><description>Looking for a customer is the same process compared to looking for a job.</description></item><item><title>Manager and Driver Pattern - pattern, implementation, and usage</title><link>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-05-driver-manager-pattern/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 08:13:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-05-driver-manager-pattern/</guid><description>Driver-based Development is a coding pattern that is common in the Laravel world and used in multiple instances in the framework.</description></item><item><title>Useful and Useless Relationship Definitions</title><link>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-05-relationships/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 14:20:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-05-relationships/</guid><description>Programmer giving Relationship Advice - A summary about Laravel / Eloquent relationships including some hints, advanced techniques to use and misuse relations Relationships are great # Relational Databases like mySql or postgres tend to have that thing called relations.</description></item><item><title>Model Specific Query Builder - an Alternative to Scopes</title><link>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-05-custom-query-builder-pattern/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 08:20:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-05-custom-query-builder-pattern/</guid><description>Scopes are nice, but by extending the Eloquent Builder for a Model enables you to add custom, model-specific methods that are often used or should have a central definition Scopes are great, but &amp;hellip; # Local scopes allow you to define common sets of query constraints that you may easily re-use throughout your application; read more in the Laravel Docs.</description></item><item><title>Demo Environments and what I learned from implementing one</title><link>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-05-demo-env/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 20:36:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.blog.philodev.one/posts/2022-05-demo-env/</guid><description>I got the task to implement a Demo environment, learned something about Laravel Factories and the usage of an environment to give possible customers / investors a taste of your product and the developers to find response time / query problems and UX bugs A &amp;ldquo;Demo&amp;rdquo; Feature Request # This card was proposed in a sprint planning and sparked a discussion around multiple problems and ideas.</description></item></channel></rss>